# **JASLEEN WALIA**

## Full-Stack Web Developer

### **ABOUT ME**

Hey there, I am a creative Web Developer with a positive attitude, open mindset, and a passion for building and designing websites. With previous experience in the tech field, I have learnt to thrive under high pressure environments with firm deadlines. I look forward to opportunities where I can contribute my skills and collaborate with a team to create quality projects.

+1 647-224-3895

jasleenwalia238@gmail.com #31-2136 Wyandotte Street West, Windsor, ON N9B 1J9

Check out my portfolio here: https://portfoliojaz.firebaseapp.com/

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Full Stack Web Developer [June 2018 – Present]

Venus Mind Media, Windsor, ON

- Create and maintain websites for small businesses such as restaurants, educational institutions, gyms etc.
- Produce dynamic user-interfaces through comprehensive research and prototype development
- Manage and execute multiple projects concurrently to meet tight deadlines
- Administer full lifecycle of software development for various projects with on-time delivery while staying 7% under budget
- Implement processes for cleanup and performance improvement that minimized downtime for the customer's website by 13%
- Use search engine optimization (SEO) best practices to optimize the website for organic search

## Teaching and Learning Project Assistant [Sept 2017 – April 2018]

University of Windsor, Windsor, ON



- Assisted the Learning Management System Team in testing several upgrades of Blackboard following a team testing procedure
- Provided support in developing a Curriculum Mapping tool to help cross-check data for learning outcomes of each course taught in the University
- Acquired hands on experience in HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript and responsive design development
- Utilized several types of CMS systems, including Drupal

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**



Master of Engineering, Co-op [Aug 2016 – Dec 2017]

University of Windsor, Windsor, ON

Become a Full-Stack Web Developer [Dec 2020]

LinkedIn Learning



#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS Web Development Technologies** SASS CSS3 JavaScript Bootstrap HTML5 92% 87% 91% 92% 93% JSON Node JS React JS Express JS 90% 93% 92% 94% **Databases** Firebase MongoDB 93% 94% Tools NPM Drupal Git/Github 80% 87% 91% **Integrated Development Environment** VS Code Sublime Atom 87% 85% 90% **Application Program Interface (API)** DropBox Google Drive OneDrive Twitter OAuth 70% 70% 80% 70% 70%